-[footsteps]
-[Xylo panting]
♪
[TEORITTA] Wait, my knight.
This is not the path
that we initially took.
We already have our next orders.
[Venetim sighs]
[XYLO] There's no
one set path for heroes.
-[birds chirping]
-[ducks quacking]
[horse neighs]
There are many more
travelers here.
[VENETIM] We're all
off to the same place,
which is holding
something of a festival.
-Quick question, Xylo.
-[XYLO] What?
[panting] I'm about to die.
Can we take a break
sooner than later?
We had one a minute ago.
[VENETIM] I can't go on.
[thuds]
Uh, is that our
next destination?
Correct.
It's a fortress
of the Second Capital.
A key part of their defenses.
[XYLO]
A natural stronghold
guarded by a river
and sheer cliffs.
[XYLO] That's Mureed Fortress.
Otherwise known
as the Wayfarer's Nest.
♪
[MERCHANT 1]
Lowest prices around!
[indistinct chatter]
♪
[merchant 2 chuckles]
Whoops,
seems you need
more military scrip.
I'll take five of these.
[POSTMAN] Does anyone here
have a letter to send out?
Send anywhere
-in the Federated Kingdom.
-Take these to my mother.
[POSTMAN] No problem!
[sighs]
[VENETIM] Fresh from repairs
and already back
to your old tricks.
You're incorrigible, Dotta.
Relax, will you?
No one's gonna get mad
over some harmless pilfering
at a festival.
We haven't attended
the Great Exchange in a while,
but don't go getting careless.
The Verkle Corp merchants
are notoriously miserly.
[exclaims]
I say we should enjoy
this while we can.
It's not often
we get to have a vacation.
Heroes like us aren't allowed
the luxury of a vacation.
Even as of now,
we're "on standby."
But that said, technically,
we're not disallowed
the occasional respite.
[Dotta sighs]
[DOTTA] That's what I said
just rephrased to make yourself
sound smarter.
[DOTTA] All we're missing is
some girls to keep us company.
[VENETIM] You're dreaming.
Even if there were
such an establishment here,
we'd never be allowed
to partake.
[DOTTA] No kidding.
[NORGALLE] Commander-in-chief,
where are you?
-Commander Xylo!
-[XYLO] Huh?
At attention,
the traveling merchants
have arrived.
Your king needs you
to procure some wine!
I'm afraid our treasury
is fairly depleted
for the time being.
Guessing you forgot
spending all of our scrip?
[Norgalle gasps]
If you want booze,
then you'll have to get
someone to take out a loan.
Someone like Venetim.
[NORGALLE] The chancellor
is keeping an eye
on that sticky-fingered Dotta.
Always has a fresh excuse
to slack off.
What of Tsav?
Has he not returned
from his mission yet?
[XYLO] No. He's still out
on loan to another unit.
[grunts]
Flagrant insubordination!
Does the crown mean
nothing anymore?
Honestly, it seems
a moment of peace
-is too much to ask.
-[panting]
There you are!
I have been searching
high and low!
-[lock rattling]
-[XYLO] Confirms my theory.
-[door opens]
-Your chamber door's unlocked.
Does that not defeat
its very purpose?
Dotta unlocked it
and scampered away.
He took the key with him.
Do you not wish to attend
the Great Exchange, my knight?
I don't wanna talk
to any damn knights.
Then come and make merry
with me instead!
I have no reason to.
Just go to the Great Exchange
yourself.
[gasps] Need I remind you that
you are addressing a goddess?
I have no interest
in such frivolity.
[Xylo scoffs]
A Holy Knight would be
happy to escort you.
[Teoritta grunts]
Let us speak no more
of the Exchange.
Instead,
I shall now grant you the honor
of playing a game with me!
Are you not elated?
[XYLO] Zig?
Venetim took it upon himself
to teach me all the rules.
I shall prove
a formidable opponent.
[Teoritta chuckles]
The trick is to use
the venerable
"hidden spear" strategy
oft utilized by the royal family
in the Kingdom of Meht.
That's enough.
If Venetim taught you that,
he was messing with you.
[gasps]
[Xylo sighs]
And besides,
I've already got plans.
What? Do you speak of that book?
Can you not study it
some other time?
Look, I even made
a bookmark for you.
I don't care, you can keep it.
♪
[TEORITTA] I must admit,
it is surprising
that you love reading so.
What manner of text
is that you're--
[XYLO] It's poetry.
Is that true?
♪
[TEORITTA]
My knight reads poetry?
[XYLO] Sure, why wouldn't I?
What manner of verse is it?
I shall allow you the privilege
of reading it to me, now.
-Denied.
-[grunts]
At the least, permit me
to read over your shoulder.
Do not be cruel.
[sighs] I don't think
a goddess would get anything
out of this book.
It's just a collection
of old poems
called Dragon-Drunk.
Written by an alcoholic poet
by the name of Altoyard Comette.
In his old age, he dreamed
of becoming a dragon,
and practiced flying every night
until it led to his demise.
[TEORITTA] Oh...
Quite the fantastical tale.
[XYLO] There were a lot of poets
like him in those days.
I might have become
a poet myself
if I hadn't joined the military.
A poet?
What of it? Why is that so--
-[KIVIA] Xylo Forbartz.
-[TEORITTA] Huh?
Finally found you.
Though I didn't expect
to also find the goddess.
Greetings, Kivia, I deem it
a most pleasant surprise
to see you here as well!
[Xylo chuckles]
So the noble captain
of the Holy Knights
has deigned to pay me a visit.
I take it our punishment
has been decided?
Either that, or a new mission.
You're correct on both counts.
Regardless,
that isn't why I'm here.
I need to have a word with you.
What about?
Follow me. I'll unlock--
[TEORITTA] I shall join you.
[XYLO] Huh?
[TEORITTA]
I have been informed
that the Great Exchange
is underway.
It seems fitting that we should
speak as we browse about.
With Kivia present,
even a goddess like me
will surely be
allowed to attend.
Indeed, truly, it must be so.
My knight,
I demand we make haste.
Fine.
♪
[indistinct chatter]
[Teoritta humming, chuckling]
-Really?
-[TEORITTA] Xylo, behold!
What is that over yonder?
Nourishment or
a decoration of some sort?
[XYLO] That's candy.
First time seeing it?
[TEORITTA] "Can-dy"?
This marvel did not yet exist
in the time I was created.
They are rather reminiscent
of shining jewels.
[gasps, sniffs]
-What is that long, thin stuff?
-[XYLO] Uh?
Fried noodles.
A western dish
of wheat-dough strips fried
in butter and fermented sauce.
How delightful!
And what are those things?
There, at the stall
with the bear sign.
[XYLO] That would be...
The hell? I'm not sure.
[KIVIA] Miwoolies Creams.
Dessert,
care of the First Capital.
It's basically shaved ice atop
a mound of whipped cream,
with some honey and nuts.
It is exquisite.
The bear is their mascot.
They are holding
a contest to name it.
[exclaims] Truly magnificent!
A testament
to cultural advancement!
Never heard of it.
But you have?
Is it that shocking?
Everybody enjoys iced treats.
♪
Out with it.
What's that look about?
[TEORITTA] Speak, my knight!
They look delectable,
do they not?
It would be a pity
to pass them by.
You cannot hide it.
You clearly wish to try one!
[sighs] All right, you win.
Grab the two that look best.
Do you want one?
I'll have to pass this time.
I've been trying
to save up my scrip.
Just two. Use this.
Go ahead.
[TEORITTA] It shall be done.
You have placed this task
in able hands! [chuckles]
Xylo,
you've given me reason
to reevaluate my opinion of you.
Huh?
You saved them.
My doomed knights
at Couveunge.
And at Zewan Gan,
you risked it all
to save those
who were prepared to abandon.
The people you saved
were grateful,
and won't soon forget you.
Good to know.
Guess it wasn't all for nothing.
Before today, I didn't realize
you could smile.
[chuckles]
I'm usually too pissed off
to muster a stupid grin.
Even so,
you've more than
proven yourself a capable ally.
Beyond that,
your pact
with Goddess Teoritta...
I believe it may have saved her.
I don't follow.
Her story is rather unusual.
She was discovered
in the northern ruins.
After her excavation,
we of the 13th Order
of Holy Knights,
assigned to pact with her,
were dispatched
to oversee the operation.
But a rift formed between
the military and Temple.
[laughs] That's a crying shame.
You dare laugh?
When you caused it
by killing goddess Senereva?
Say what?
[KIVIA] After what transpired,
the military started
having ideas.
"If we're capable
of killing a goddess,
perhaps we also have the power
to create more of them."
It was decided
the military would
use Teoritta for research.
[Xylo chuckles]
Why bother calling it research?
They really meant "dissection."
True.
The temple opposed the notion,
but the military won out
in the end.
However, that situation
has started to change.
In a short span of time,
your unit has taken out
two Demon Lords,
thus, proving the usefulness
of Goddess Teoritta.
What do you mean
her "usefulness"?
Are you saying they thought
she was useless before that?
How would they even know
when they had just found her?
We knew she possessed
the power to summon swords.
It was inscribed in the ruins
where she was found.
[Xylo grunts]
♪
[KIVIA] It is said
the goddesses came to us
during the First War
of Subjugation,
in what is known
as the Great Civilized Era.
The goddesses serve
as a "gate" of sorts,
and each one,
possesses a different nature.
One creates
various poisons.
One calls down lightning
and raging storms.
One foresees the future.
They awaken in response
to Demon Blights.
When their task is fulfilled,
they return to their coffins
to slumber.
I'm already well-informed
about the goddesses' power.
There's even a rumor
that one of them
brought Tatsuya here
from another world.
It was judged that the ability
to summon swords
wasn't good enough.
That it was far weaker
than the abilities
of the 12 other goddesses.
We knew that. Knew her fate.
Yet despite that,
we were still complicit.
Oh, I see.
That explains a lot.
So your suicidal plan
in Couveunge
was just a sorry attempt
to atone for your sins.
[Kivia grunts]
[XYLO] It's despicable,
even if she was
a useless goddess.
Here, please enjoy!
You have my gratitude!
Xylo, mission accomplished!
I purchased one for Kivia, too!
[Kivia gasps]
[Teoritta chuckles]
Come, you two, let us...
[exclaims] Hey!
[sighs]
[groans]
Tell me about our next mission.
Why now?
If we keep doing a good job,
she's less likely
to get dissected, right?
[Kivia gasps]
Not sure what their
definition of "usefulness" is,
but I'll make those
Galtuile bastards choke on it.
[KIVIA] Hm.
Defense.
That's why
your hero unit is here.
You'll defend this fortress
by yourselves...
To the death.
To the death? Really?
That's right.
You will defend the fortress
from the Demon Blight
without backup
until the bitter end.
So it's a literal
suicide mission.
Hey, Xylo, I need you
to keep your cool.
Don't snap
and beat anyone to death--
What the hell kind of animal
do you think I am?
[VENETIM] Pardon me,
could you perhaps tell us more?
Such as the fine details
of this strategy?
[commander snorts]
[COMMANDER] You'll stay here
at the fortress.
That is all.
A war of attrition, then.
And how long
do you need us to hold out?
Until you die.
-[Xylo grunts]
-Oh.
That's the plan.
The Ninth and Thirteenth Orders
will be at the rear,
watching and conserving
their strength.
Once you're all dead
and the fortress has been taken,
that will be their cue
to unleash a special attack.
And what exactly might that be?
It's poison.
The ninth goddess will perform
a miracle for all to see.
[Xylo scoffs]
[XYLO] You think that will
kill the Demon Lord?
I hear you've been throwing
everything you have at it,
yet you still haven't managed
to defeat it.
That is accurate.
Our last plan
involved an ace sniper.
He delivered
the goddess' poison directly.
His efforts merely
induced a torpor
the beast easily
recovered from.
Even someone like Tsav
wasn't able to take it down?
Between that humbling outcome
and a vision of the future
from the third goddess,
Galtuile decided
to revise the plan.
That was the birth
of our strategy
to set a massive trap
in Mureed Fortress.
It ends here.
We'll poison the Demon Lord
until it's dead.
So the idea is to
effectively cancel out
its ability to regenerate?
Meanwhile, we're to wait around
and buy you some time
until we die?
[COMMANDER] That is correct.
May Mureed Fortress become
the eternal resting ground
for Demon Blight
Number 15, "Iblis."
[VENETIM] I have a question,
Commander.
Is there any reason
we can't leave?
I mean, after luring
the Demon Lord
into the trap, of course.
The reason is that
those are Galtuile's orders.
If any of you attempt to leave
the fortress prematurely,
the sacred seals
on your necks
will kill the entire unit
instantly.
[gasps] The entire unit?
Well, then.
Is that necessary?
Or is there some
compelling reason
you want us dead?
[gasps]
[scoffs] So their hatred
demands our suffering.
Understood.
We'll carry out the plan.
-[gasps]
-[VENETIM] That said,
I'd like to propose
a few revisions,
if you don't mind.
Like what?
[VENETIM] Simple.
That pesky caveat
that we all blow up
even if one of us
leaves the fortress...
It's highly counterproductive.
How so?
I'm sure I don't need
to remind you
that we're
antisocial criminal miscreants,
so it's a forgone conclusion
that at least one of our ranks
will try to save his own skin,
making success impossible.
Here's a thought.
Kill us if we all leave,
or one bad apple will inevitably
spoil the whole mission.
That tiny change
would substantially increase
our chances of success.
Oh, one more thing,
regarding Goddess Teoritta...
Our goddess is kind.
The most compassionate soul
I've ever encountered.
Even if ordered to leave,
she'll wish to stay by our side.
I request that that be allowed.
Ha!
I don't have the authority
to approve it.
That's not my call to make.
The goddess is under
the jurisdiction of the 13--
Hey, Xylo,
go and request permission
from Captain Kivia.
On it.
What else do you want me
to get for us?
We're going to need
more soldiers.
Understood. What else?
Weapons and provisions.
Isn't there anything else
you want?
-A pardon.
-[VENETIM] Understood.
-What else?
-[Xylo sighs, grunts]
[XYLO] Forget the pardon.
I want cavalry
and some artillery.
Can you get Jayce
and Rhyno back?
[VENETIM] I'm afraid they're
still on the western front.
We might be able
to get Tsav back, though.
Tsav, huh?
[COMMANDER] Hey, what are you
discussing over there?
[VENETIM] Listen, Xylo.
That's not where
Captain Kivia's room is,
so don't waste your time.
[XYLO] Oh, right.
[VENETIM] Go on.
I'll make sure everything
is handled here.
Just trust me and relax.
[XYLO] I know you
too well to trust you.
Can you really pull it off?
Funny you should ask.
Though I highly doubt
you'll take me at my word.
Despite how I look,
you should know,
there was a time
when yours truly
was on the verge
of saving the whole world.
I must say,
this is rather dreary.
I take it this means
I'm not being granted
a proper trial?
A thousand pardons,
Venetim Leopool.
I would have preferred to speak
in a slightly nicer location.
Honestly, I was hoping
our paths would cross.
I have a great deal
of respect for you.
That so?
Do you hope to pursue
a career as a con man too?
If that's the case,
I really don't see why you would
admire someone like me,
seeing as how I got
caught and all.
Right you are.
I completely agree with you.
[VENETIM] Regarding the crime
I'm being charged with,
I suppose attempting
to sell off the royal palace
to the circus
was a bridge too far?
True. You elevated fraud
to a whole new level.
Fabricating a mad story
about the entire capital
being relocated
in order to sell the land
to a circus performing
in the area.
Quite the talent.
I intended to take
the advance payment and leave,
but things got out of hand.
There's investment fraud
not to mention
forgery
and counterfeiting to boot.
I have at least
a hundred complaints here
from the Verkle Development
Corporation.
[VENETIM] I'm so sorry.
Truly, I am.
Spare me your apologies.
Tell me,
what first inspired your choice
to become a con man?
[VENETIM] Good question.
It's hard to say,
I guess I've always hated
seeing people look disappointed.
So I'd lie my way out
of any tough situation,
then do the work
to make the lie consistent.
I can't imagine how much effort
that must have entailed,
and it's impressive
that you managed
to keep such a large-scale
operation equally consistent.
[VENETIM] Thank you.
So, um,
should I be bracing myself
for the death penalty?
Actually,
your fate is far worse.
We have no intention
of punishing you
for the fraud
or any of your other crimes.
So it's not the fraud?
Then, why--
[KAFZEN]
This is the true culprit.
[VENETIM] You mean that
third-rate gossip rag
I used to write drivel for?
What about it?
[KAFZEN] There's
a certain article you wrote.
Spies controlled
by the Demon Blight,
and masquerading as humans.
You boldly assert that
they've infiltrated the Temple,
as well as Galtuile
and even the royal family.
Right, they were
out of goddess scandals,
as well as those
about the Holy Knights,
and even the stuff
about the royal family.
To drive sales,
they told me
they wanted an article
that would inspire fear
in the populace.
[KAFZEN] Well,
to be completely frank,
fraud isn't a problem,
or forgery, inflated scandals,
conspiracy theories.
Those are all fine.
That said,
we can't have you going around
telling the truth.
[VENETIM] Huh?
You have a particular talent
for being able
to convince people
of the most outrageous things.
You're at least skilled enough
to make us believe
you can achieve anything
with your words.
Wait, this is a huge mistake.
Just give me a second
and I'll explain--
To prevent you from
speaking truth in the future,
we're going to be including
a special feature
in your sacred seal.
What? Please, no! [grunts]
-Stop! Just wait a minute!
-I'm afraid the death penalty
is too good
for someone like you.
[VENETIM] You...
You can't. I swear,
I don't know anything!
I just...
didn't want
to disappoint anyone.
[Kafzen chuckles]
Venetim Leopool.
-You are hereby sentenced...
-[Venetim whimpers]
...to be a hero.
[XYLO] I can't believe he got us
everything I asked for,
except the pardon.
[DOTTA]
If the goddess is in danger,
I'd bet good scrip that
Venetim will conjure up some way
to get her out of it.
He's the cleverest guy I know.
Some way,
he's guaranteed to wind up
with a knife in his back.
Speaking of,
do you think that Tsav
has already arrived?
Probably.
[sighs]
Somehow, that guy found a way
to be even worse than Venetim.
You know...
Tsav is just so volatile
all the time.
-[indistinct chatter]
-[MAN 1] He did it again!
[MAN 2] That man is unstoppable!
[MAN 3] Seven times in a row!
[man 4 grunts]
[all exclaiming]
[MAN 5]
Yet another winning roll!
[laughs]
Looks like the pot's all mine!
Go on. It's time to pony up
my hard-earned scrip!
You should know, I can see
right through your little ploy.
Huh?
Somethin' you wanna say?
Actually, there is.
I happen to have
keen eyes and ears.
Also,
I'm a brutally stand-up guy
who just hates to see
wrongdoers go unpunished.
But if you give up the scrip
and leave, I won't have
-to teach you a lesson--
-[MAN 6] You bastard!
You'd better shut your mouth!
Take back those damn lies
-or else I'm gonna...
-[sword whooshes]
[whimpering]
-[TSAV] We all saw that, right?
-[all gasping]
Relieved the naughty fraudster
of his swindling hand.
[screaming]
It's your own fault.
I tried to warn you in advance.
[screaming continues]
[TSAV] But anyway...
[Tsav grunts]
[Tsav sighs]
I think it's dinner time.
[♪ closing theme song playing]